Their American dream is bigger than yours.
Pain & Gain is a comedy, crime, action film directed by Michael Bay.
Daniel Lugo, manager of the Sun Gym in 1990s Miami, decides that there is only
one way to achieve his version of the American dream: extortion.
To achieve his goal, he recruits musclemen Paul and Adrian as accomplices.
After several failed attempts, they abduct rich businessman Victor
Kershaw and convince him to sign over all his assets to them.
But when Kershaw makes it out alive, authorities
are reluctant to believe his story.
Daniel Lugo, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Paul Doyle, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Adrian Doorbal, played by Anthony Mackie.
Victor Kershaw, played by Tony Shalhoub.
Ed DuBois, played by Ed Harris.
John Mese, played by Rob Corddry.
Pain & Gain is a 2013 American black comedy crime film directed by Michael
Bay and written by Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely.
It is based on a 1999 series of Miami New Times articles by Pete Collins about the activities of the Sun Gym gang, a group of
bodybuilding ex-convicts convicted of kidnapping, extortion, torture, and murder in Miami in the mid-1990s.
It stars Mark Wahlberg, Dwayne Johnson, and Anthony Mackie as members of the
gang, with supporting roles played by Tony Shalhoub and Ed Harris.
The title is a play on the fitness adage "no pain, no gain".
Pain & Gain premiered in Miami on April 11, 2013, before
Paramount Pictures released it in theatres on April 26.
The film received mixed reviews; it was praised for its script and performances, but
criticized for its directing, historical inaccuracies, and overreliance on violence.
A commercial success, it grossed $86 million worldwide
against a $26 million production budget.
Marc Schiller, the Sun Gym gang's primary victim who was depicted in the film as
Victor Kershaw, sued the production company over his portrayal.
The film explores themes of miami, florida, scam, weight
lifting, weightlifting, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.